Brian Beal

Software Developer Freelancer

Alpharetta, GA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Brian-Beal/f65791f672d85329

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Freelance - Atlanta, GA - October 2014 to July 2017

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a highly-skilled software development professional bringing more than three years in software design, development and integration. Manifesting advanced knowledge of PHP, Javascript, and MySQL. I have knowledge in the ecommerce and customer retail management environment. Managed and assisted clients with multiple webpage and retail instances.

SKILLS

- o Innovative
- o Data management
- o API design knowledge
- o Advanced knowledge of PHP
- o Exceptional time management
- o Advanced problem solving skills
- o E-commerce background
- o Troubleshooting and debugging
- o Performance and scalability optimization

WORK HISTORY

OCTOBER 2014 – JULY 2017 Software Developer Freelancer | Remote

- Integrated SOAP, Web, REST APIs for merchant gateway companies, fulfillment companies, fraud prevention companies, data migrations, and call center service plugins using PHP, XML, and Javascript.
- Designed mobile desktop responsive webpages using HTML, CSS, native Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, and Bootstrap for sale funnel purposes including merchant gateway and WordPress integrations.
- Regulated, tested and created Affiliate pixel firing system, CRM SDK for webpage transaction purposes, Export/Import FTP and API Postback system, User Access Level system, Payout Commission system, Pre-Paid Auto-Transaction system, Customer Blacklist feature, exclusive CRM data migration plugins, Decline Salvage feature, and various campaign, product, and user interface customer configuration updates in an MVC environment using Agile and SCRUM.

- Utilized PHP and MySQL to create and update interactive Javascript charts: transaction, retention, fulfillment, projection, conversion, chargeback, card processing reports, etc.
- Created documentation intended for software configurations and Web APIs using CRUD displayed in JSON in order to manipulate relational database in MySQL.
- Orchestrated and developed scheduled task scripts and utilized task logs to troubleshoot client issues and misbehavior processes of task.
- Developer environment managed and maintained with version control procedures using Git.
- Implemented and conducted training for client and fellow staff on utilizing the CRM application software, integrations, and featured configurations.
- Performed troubleshooting to clients' CRM and webpage issues and maintained documentation of all reported issues via email, Skype, 24/7 hour support line, and ticketing system. All activities and project documented via project tracking software titled Jira.

EDUCATION

BS in Software Engineer

Herzing University Atlanta - Alpharetta, GA October 2014 to July 2017